boehringer-ingelheim.com 2016-04-13

# Privacy Statement

Boehringer Ingelheim International GmbH (hereafter "Boehringer Ingelheim") takes the protection of your personal data seriously. This privacy statement describes what personal data are collected by this website and how these data are processed. The nature, extent and purpose of the collection and processing of personal data depend on the actions of the user during the visit of this website. In any event, collection and processing of personal data will only take place conformable to the applicable law.  

### Login to Password Protected Areas  

When you login to a protected area of the website or when you order information material, Boehringer Ingelheim may ask you to provide personal data (in particular full name, email address, and – where required e.g. for the purpose of the area you login to – postal address, profession and other information). Where providing such data is not mandatory for the login or order, this is indicated.

Where necessary, you can modify the data entered by editing your account/profile (in case of a password-protected area) or by sending an email to [info@boehringer-ingelheim.com](mailto:info@boehringer-ingelheim.com) asking to have your account data modified. 

### Log data  

When using the website, temporarily certain data, including data sent by your browser (IP address, cookies, referring web page, time and date, content viewed) will be stored. As far as such data is personal data, Boehringer Ingelheim will, unless you have otherwise given your consent, only use such data where required for the use of the website (including for maintenance reasons such as preventing attacks), for statistical purposes and/or to fulfil a contract with you. 

Boehringer Ingelheim will also use this information in pseudonymized form in order to design and improve the website in a needs-based manner. You can find more information regarding this in the "Cookies" section.  

### Data Transfer to Third Parties  

Boehringer Ingelheim only transfers personal data to third parties when you have expressly given your consent, when required to deliver services that you want to use, or when the data transfer is otherwise justified under the applicable law and it is made sure that your legitimate interests are observed.  Boehringer Ingelheim undertakes to provide an adequate protection of personal data transferred outside of the European Union, regardless whether such data is processed by other Boheringer Ingelheim group companies or other third parties.  

### Information Requests; Right to Withdraw Consent  

On your request, we will inform you in writing or electronically whether and what data relating to you Boehringer Ingelheim has stored and will review any requests you may have to delete, correct or block personal data. Please send your request to: 

Boehringer Ingelheim International GmbH  
\- Data Protection Officer –  
Binger Straße 173  
D-55216 Ingelheim am Rhein  
Germany 

Email: [datenschutz@boehringer-ingelheim.com](mailto:datenschutz@boehringer-ingelheim.com)

The same applies if you want to withdraw a consent you may have given to the collection and/or processing of your personal data. Such consent can be withdrawn at any time with effect for the future by mail or email to the above addresses.  

### Cookies  

[]()This website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file, downloaded on to a device when the user accesses certain websites. Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to recognize your device on subsequent visits to provide information to the owners of the site. 

If you do not want cookies on your computer (or other device), you can deactivate them in your browser settings. However, deactivating cookies may affect the usability and functionality of this website.

This website uses the following categories of cookies: 

**I. Necessary cookies**

Necessary cookies are used for "technical" reasons, such as re-establishing a user’s session at login if their previous session was cancelled due to user inactivity. Such cookies are not used to analyse use of our website.

 **II. Analytics**

These cookies help us analyzing use of our website and identify options for improvement:

  **Webtrends**

Boehringer Ingelheim uses cookies and technology by Webtrends to analyse traffic use in order to improve our website. You can, at any time and with effect for the future, opt-out of the data collection associated with this technology. To opt out, follow this link: https://ondemand.webtrends.com/support/optout.asp  
When opting out, a cookie will be placed on your machine, with the sole purpose to prevent (for the future) that any of your actions when using your internet browser become a part of the pseudonymous usage analysis described above.
